No one can outrun their destiny.
Apocalypto is a action, drama, history film directed by Mel Gibson.
Set in the Mayan civilization, when a man's idyllic presence is brutally disrupted by a violent invading force, he is
taken on a perilous journey to a world ruled by fear and oppression where a harrowing end awaits him.
Through a twist of fate and spurred by the power of his love for his woman and his family he
will make a desperate break to return home and to ultimately save his way of life.
Jaguar Paw, played by Rudy Youngblood.
Zero Wolf, played by Raoul Max Trujillo.
Middle Eye, played by Gerardo Taracena.
Sky Flower, played by Iazua Larios.
Chilam, played by Antonio Monroy.
Mother in Law, played by María Isabel Díaz Lago.
Apocalypto () is a 2006 epic historical action-adventure film  produced and
directed by Mel Gibson, who co-wrote the screenplay with Farhad Safinia.
The film features a cast of Indigenous and Mexican actors consisting of Rudy Youngblood, Raoul Trujillo, Mayra Sérbulo, Dalia Hernández, Gerardo
Taracena, Jonathan Brewer, Rodolfo Palacios, Bernardo Ruiz Juarez, Ammel Rodrigo Mendoza, Ricardo Diaz Mendoza, and Israel Contreras.
Set in Yucatán around the year 1511, Apocalypto portrays the hero's journey of a young man named Jaguar Paw,
a late Mesoamerican hunter and his fellow tribesmen who are captured by an invading force.
After a raid on their village, they are brought on a perilous journey to a Maya city
for human sacrifice at a time when the Maya civilization is in decline.
Principal photography took place in Mexico from November 21, 2005 to July 2006.
All dialogue is in a modern approximation of the ancient language of the setting, and the Indigenous
Yucatec Mayan language is spoken with subtitles, which sometimes refer to the language as Mayan.
Apocalypto was distributed by Buena Vista Pictures in North America and
Icon Film Distribution in the United Kingdom and Australia.
The film was a box office success, grossing over $120 million worldwide, and received generally positive reviews, with critics praising Gibson's direction, Dean
Semler's cinematography, and the performances of the cast, though the portrayal of Maya civilization and perceived historical inaccuracies were criticized.
The film explores themes of loss of loved one, maya
civilization, village, solar eclipse, slavery.
The tone is dark and emotional and mind_bending.